Question: You have received the
quarterly numbers of ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company, so
we will talk about the same in this video
and will know whether you should
invest in ICICI Lombard
or not, so let's start, so
first of all if we talk about the total revenue here, then the
total revenue of the company has
fallen on quarterly basis to Rs. 4 crore, here the
total revenue of the company has come out, now
what is the reason for the fall in revenue, the
premium collection had swelled due to the second wave of liquidity
and
apart from that the new policies made here are also
not made as much as they are
made every time, now look here is the
Jio net profit of the company, it has
fallen by fifty percent on quarterly basis to Rs. 151
crore, here the total net
profit of the company has come out, now
why did the profitability of the company fall so much, the
previous revision is that of the claims, which have
doubled in comparison to the previous quarter  It has also increased
but you should have known that this is the
company's revenue of Rs 6 crore from Ujjain to Phathi
and the total claim that the company has is
around Rs 1100 crore but if you get a
claim of 30 percent of the total revenue of the company then
what will be left with you for ads. For Rishi, here
Jio's net profit seems to be falling
but if we
compare it with the April to June quarter of last year then in
comparison to this the revenue has increased by two percent
and that too by 18 percent so this Rauniyar
Vaishya revenue has increased but the
profitability has fallen on a yearly basis
and has fallen even more on a quarterly basis.
See that here the
net profit of the company has fallen by 22% to Rs 11051 crore.
Here the total net profit of the company came out to be Rs 11051 crore.
Now the
problem mail question will be that if the
revenue of the company is increasing then
why is the profitability decreasing  If this is happening then the reason comes out in that also,
if you see the revenue of Glam Diva company last year,
till the company's revenue of 2728 Chowk Road, the
claims of the company were worth Rs 500 crores and now those
claims have been taken for 11 Ashok Road, see
how big is the revenue of the company
from Rs 300 crores and how big are the claims,
from Rs 500 crores directly to Rs 1100 crores, that is, you will see that the
claims of the company were
big here and till last the company had
earned a net profit of Rs 1.8 crores
and now the company had
earned a total net profit of Rs 151 crores, the main reason here is the
claim festival, otherwise it is invisible, in my opinion, the
second of the big claims here, the main issue of Kuber is also very big,
if you see,
health insurance was given under general insurance,
you have to understand this thing that whatever
you
went to Kwangcho, your shop insurance would be
Om insurance, health
insurance also comes under it in a volume, definitely
here  It was seen playing within general insurance,
and apart from life insurance, there was
health insurance here.
Look at this company's
market cap of ₹190 crore, if you look at it
in comparison to the industry, you would see a
trend at premium valuation here.
But if you look at the company's
results, the company's
share price will fall on the running, and at least at the current
price of the company, it will be
seen going above 50 on the running price.
But look, I think as a
long-term investor, you should
not take this company's results in a negative way at all because this is
very penetrative, it is very
penetrative. Story-2:
Very good growth is available here in the coming times.
People have realized
how important insurance is, and in our India, only
12820 per cent of the population
is insured, whether it is life insurance
or general insurance,
very good growth is available here in the coming times.
ICICI Bank has passbook customers,
so if they take any loan,
home loan, etc., then they take the
phone number from ICICI Lombard
and then take a construction loan, then even
there, if you see that
ICICI Bank has a very good customer base for direct insurance policies, then
direct benefit was
visible in ICICI Lombard.
Now look at this, look at the grade, in this way, we see the
company's revenue
increasing every year and if you
look at the profitability, the
company's profitability is increasing every year.
If you say one bed quarter, then there are
two companies for one bed. Now, when it is happening for the
first time
that the second unit of Kashmir will continue to
run in Kuber's second unit, the roads and the
debt will keep increasing, so people will keep paying
claims for the health insurance they have taken, this is
not going to happen, so for this you will have to
understand these things, if you have taken a long-term policy then
In the short term, you can move your stop a little today, so
your behavior should not change there.
And here my team member
forgot to put the price in Next Worli,
but this talk is around 1500
and today this talk is on the order till now and
its all time high of 1628 is your obtained
like share and you are getting it at a discount of 4 to 5 percent.
Now
if you look at the numbers of Bajaj Finance, it is also
negative, but if
you look at the stock performance, today the current went up by 4 to 5 percent.
Now apart from that, ICICI
Prudential, the company which launched the report,
went on talk music, so
what is the result behind this and
if this is a bad quarter for the market, then the performance of the company is going to be bad.
If
we talk about vigilance instead, then their
management had already said that this
quarter of ours is going to be bad, that there are
errors in the collection, so similarly,
we
see this happening here in ICICI Lombard.  Earlier, the
results of life insurance had also come here,
then there was Bajaj Finserv, theirs too.
If we talk about the general insurance business, then the
numbers there were dishing out,
but still,
we see the stock going up here, so that is why we have to
understand why this bad quarter is a
cup of sugar for an individual
and grow your portfolio, so
remain long-term investors and those who
want to invest could definitely invest in it.
And if we look at it now, if
you look at general insurance, if
we talk about male private players,
Kotak General Insurance is
not listed yet, but here
ICICI Lombard is getting a good premium. I hope
you must have come to know everything about ICICI Lombard quarterly numbers. If
you have any preference, please comment and I will
definitely reply to your comment. Okay
friends, thank you. Have a nice day.